

Jaeyong Lee South Korean, Age 30

Address: Väinö Auerin Katu 1 N 047, 00560, Helsinki, Finland, Mobile: +358 (0)46 577 5140, E-mail: mailto:jaeyonglee05@gmail.com, Portfolio: www.studiojaeyonglee.com, LinkedIn: https://fi.linkedin.com/in/jaeyonglee05

PROFILE

I am a UX/ Visual designer who has 4 years of professional working experience in the fields of UX, UI, product design and animation. I endeavor to create optimal user experience by transforming complex design issues to insightful and effective visual languages through UX strategy, UI design, interaction design, information visualization and user research.

I have been selected as a full scholarship student by National Institute for International Education(NIIED) for my master's study. I have successfully finished my master's thesis with Philips – 'Visual communication for behavior changes; changing users' behaviors regarding air quality'.

EXPERIENCE

Jan.2016~Oct.2016	Philips	Helsinki, Finland
	Master Thesis Student	
	- Title: Visual communication for behavior change: changing users' behaviors regarding air qu	ality
	- Created a new concept 'Smart Air Detector' and renewed UI design of Philips Smart Air – mob	ile application
Sep. 2015~Nov .2015	Philips	Singapore
	Design Intern	
	- Created information visualizations for Primary Care Project in healthcare business	
	- Developed UI design for Philips Online Shop Singapore website	
	- Responsible for creating graphics for internal company event: Town Hall Event	
Apr.2015~Aug.2015	Aalto University	Helsinki, Finland
	Teaching Assistant	
	- Responsible for building the visual identity of Experience-Driven Design course	
	 Built visual designs for brochures and a digital presentation while communicating with all sto students and companies 	ıkeholders: teachers,
	- Managed the processes of summarizing final deliverables which students created.	
Jan. 2012~Apr .2014	0100 Design <i>Studio, Product & Interior Design Company</i> Visual Designer	Seoul, South Korea
	- Designed trophies representing the EXPO 2012 YEOSU KOREA.	
	- Developed visual concepts of interior and furniture designs for the new library in Chonbuk No	tional University
	- Built holistic visual identity of 0100design: logo, visual concepts and company website	
Jan.2011~Dec.2011	KEIDA studio, <i>Design & Art Studio</i> Co-founder, Visual Designer	Seoul, South Korea
	- Awarded Red Dot Concept Design Award 2012 through 'Traveler's Paper Kit'.	
	- Conducted various artistic experiments, design campaigns for social issues, concept designs and product designs	
	- Participated in various art exhibitions: TETSUSON, Modern Haute Couture Exhibition and San	gsangmadang
Jan.2011~Mar.2011	FS Korea LTD, cosmetic container design & production company	Seoul, South Korea
	Product Design Intern	
	- Designed cosmetic containers and conducted market researches	
Jan.2009~Aug.2009	Floating Island, animation and graphic design company	Seoul, South Korea
	Visual Designer	
	- Developed visual designs for a short animation film – White Ball	
	- Developed color concepts of animation in 'Let's go MBA,' which was broadcasted on SBS.	
EDUCATION		
Aug. 2014~Present	Aalto University, Master of Arts	Helsinki, Finland

Collaborative and Industrial Design, School of Arts, Design and Architecture

Specialization in creating visual communication design for behavior change: UX, UI, interaction, information visualization and service design through various design researches and design strategies

- Created an online booking service for Kalasatama hospital
- Created a welding training application for Kemppi
- Created a visual identity for Experience-Driven Design course in Aalto University

Jun.2015~Aug.2015

Aalto University, Master of Arts (Minor)

Helsinki, Finland

Information Technology Program – Strategy and Experience Design

- 4.25 / 4.5 scale
- Developed the digital service of www.vero.fi for Verohallinto: the Finnish Tax Administration
- Presented design solutions rebuilding information structure of Vero.fi with the 'Life Event' concept at the end of the program.

Selected as a full scholarship student by National Institute for International Education (NIIED) for

Mar. 2005~Feb. 2012

Hongik University, Bachelor of Fine Arts

Seoul, South Korea

Visual Communication Design

Metal Art and Design

- Cumulative GPA: 4.04 / 4.5 scale; Merit-based Scholarship Recipient five times
- Served military service between Jul. 2006 and Jul. 2008 in South Korea ROK army headquarters.

AWARD & HONOR

Aug.2014

Aug.2014	Selected as a full scribialship student by National Institute for international Education (Niled) for		
	2 years.	South Korea	
	 Selected as a representative scholarship student by NIIED which is run by Korean Government, and ful master's degree studies for 2 years. 	lly supported for	
Apr.2014	2014 Character & Marketing Design Award of LOTTE World Tower Mall, 3 rd prize - Winning work: Lopy, Mascot design of Lotte World Tower Mall and relevant applications design	South Korea	
Sep. 2013	2013 Red Dot Concept Design Award, Honorable Mention - Winning work: Life-Light, emergency directional system for vulnerable people	Germany	
Sep. 2012	2012 Red Dot Concept Design Award, Winner - Winning work: Traveler's Paper Kit, emergency paper kit for travelers	Germany	
Aug. 2012	Korea Good Design Award, Good Design Selection - Winning work: Triangle Gate, optical electronic gate indicating obvious direction	South Korea	
Nov. 2011	6th Recycling of Resource Junk Art Contest, Encouragement prize - Winning work: Spectacle #1, Junk Art using abandoned electronic devices and video	South Korea	
Sep. 2008	Korean Association Against Drug Abuse Cartoon Contest, Excellence Award - Winning work: Too dangerous to touch, a story about dangerousness of having drugs	South Korea	
TEACHING AC	TIVITY		
Jan. 2012~Oct. 2012	Clay Gim Art Institute Tutor	South Korea	
	- Private Art Institute for children from 5 to 10		
Mar. 2005~Jul. 2006	Jeon Won Art Institute Tutor	South Korea	
INTERESTS	- Private Art Institute for art college prep students		
	Interests include animation film making (have directed two short animation films), drawing, learning coding and playing sports such as badminton and football.		
SKILLS			
Excellent	Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, InVision, After Effects, Premiere Pro, Audition, InDesign, Muse	2	
Good	MS Office, 3D Max, Maya, CAD, HTML		
Basic	Rhino, CSS, Processing		
LANGUAGE			
Mother tongue	Korean		
Fluent	English		
Basic	Japanese		

Jaeyong Lee